Julian Stein Creative Developer Los Angeles, CA julian.stein@gmail.com <u>julianstein.net</u> portfolio.julianstein.net

EDUCATION

University of California Los Angeles, MFA Design Media Arts, 2019 **Concordia University**, BFA Electroacoustic Studies, 2012

BACKGROUND

Creative Developer

Self-Employed

Los Angeles, CA | June 2017 - Present

Constructs bespoke experiences for physical and web-based environments, giving careful attention to design and interaction. Works with clients including artists, musicians, agencies, and institutions to realize creative ventures, crafting each project through code, fabrication, and custom electronics.

Media Artist

Los Angeles, CA | June 2011 - Present

Creates performances and installations that examine relationships between the analog and the digital, often taking form as generative art, kinetic sculpture, and audiovisual performance. Uses technology to reimagine aspects of daily life, highlighting rhythmic and patterned structures to seek out shared qualities between the natural and built world. Exhibited work at renowned global venues, including *The Kitchen* (NYC), *Musée des arts et métier* (Paris, FR), *Edith-Russ-Haus* (Oldenburg, GE), and *MUTEK Barcelona*.

SELECT PROJECTS

Time is Out of Joint, CalArts, Exhibition Website, 2020 Web Designer + Developer, React (Gatsby.js)

Artificial Ecologies, **CultureHub**, Virtual Exhibition, 2020 Web Developer: WebGL

Whispering Wishes, **Plan8**, Sound Installation, 2019 Software Developer: Responsive Sound Design, Max/MSP

MindTravel, **Murray Hidary**, Audiovisual Experience, 2017 Software Developer: Generative Visuals, Max/MSP

EXPERIENCE

Creative Technologist

CultureHub

Los Angeles | Feb 2020 - Feb 2021

Through residencies, live productions, and educational programming, CultureHub advances the work of artists experimenting with emerging technologies in search of new artistic forms.

Provided technical consultation and support to resident artists. Collaborated on creative-coding and web-development projects using *WebGL (Three.js)*, *WebRTC, and Max/MSP.* Produced live-streaming performance events using *OBS Studio* and in-house software *LiveLab*.

Julian Stein Creative Developer Los Angeles, CA julian.stein@gmail.com <u>julianstein.net</u> portfolio.julianstein.net

EXPERIENCE

Media Environment Lead

Synthesis Center, Arizona State University Tempe, AZ | 2015 - 2018

Synthesis Center (ASU) is an atelier-based research center that utilizes techniques from responsive environments and non-anthropocentric design to build an ecology of practices for re-imagining and re-making the spaces we inhabit.

Lead developer (*Max/MSP*) of a compositional toolkit to aid students, faculty, and visiting artists in developing responsive media projects involving sound, video, and light. Incorporated emerging technologies into a black-box research facility, creating flexible hardware solutions to aid in the production of expressive media works. Lead artist for *Time Lenses*, a responsive video installation presented at the *Musée des arts et métier* in Paris, France.

Research Associate

Hexagram, Concordia University, Montréal, QC | 2010 - 2015

Hexagram (Concordia University) is an interdisciplinary network dedicated to research-creation addressing the relationships between arts, cultures and technologies

Researcher at *matralab*, an interdisciplinary arts lab that places technology at the intersection of music composition and improvisation. At *matralab*, I was a sound designer and software developer (Max/MSP) – specifically for the design of interactive music scores.

Researcher at the *Topological Media Lab (TML)*, an interdisciplinary arts lab that leads art-based experiments stemming from phenomenological, social & computational perspectives. At the *TML*, I designed responsive media experiences for everyday spaces.

SKILLS

Creative Coding
Web Development
JavaScript Frameworks
WebGL
Web Design
Physical Computing
Digital Fabrication
Interaction Design

Max/MSP/Jitter, PureData, p5.js HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GraphQL, Netlify React, Gatsby.js, Next.js, Redux Three.js, Cables.gl Figma, Adobe Creative Suite Arduino, EAGLE, Custom PCBs Fusion 360, 3D Printing, CNC